## KIA ORA, I AM

# TISHA NAICKER. (she/her)

### 3RD YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT









naicker.tisha@gmail.com

@tishanaicker

https://tnai255.github.io/TishaNaickerPortfolio/

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am in my third year of a Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) degree specialising in Software at the University of Auckland. My love and incredible passion for coding have led me to look for internship opportunities that utilise knowledge specific to my software engineering career. A little bit about me, I enjoy being creative through drawing and painting, and I would go to an escape room regularly if I could because I love problem-solving to escape them!

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (HONOURS) SPECIALISING IN SOFTWARE**

University of Auckland | Jan 2021 - Present (Graduation Year: 2024)

- Cumulative GPA of 8.56 / 9.00
- Part II: A+ for Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Engineering Design 1, Software Quality Assurance, Object-Oriented Programming, Software Engineering Theory, Computer Engineering, Mathematical Modelling 2, Professional Skills and Comms

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### STUDENT TRAINING IN ENGINEERING PROGRAM INTERN | **GOOGLE, SYDNEY**

**NOV 2022 - PRESENT** 

- Collaboratively worked on a FrontEnd project through pair programming.
- · Consistently using the developer workflow to effectively improve the project.
- · Actively communicating with UX and Software Engineers to gain feedback and ensure the project has the endusers in mind.
- Parts of the project progressed to being launched internally.

#### SALES ASSISTANT | SMIGGLE, MANUKAU

OCT 2020 - FEB 2022

- Ensured I used excellent customer service skills such as welcoming, being a good listener to their needs, interests and always doing right by them.
- Efficiently and effectively met average transaction value and unit per transaction goals.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

I am proficient in Java, HTML, CSS, C, and MATLAB programming languages. I am familiar with Git, Collaborate Git, and GitHub as version control systems. Here are a few projects I have done:

- Quick, Draw! Game | Java & JavaFX | Group Project | 2022
  - o Created a fully-fledged game with creative graphics, animations, game modes, badges, scores, and user profiles as well as involved Machine Learning concepts. (Video demo on my website)
  - Iteratively improved and developed this project based on client requirements and design meetings.
  - Received the "Most Awesome Game" award for the course showcase by a Game Design Expert
- Black Jack Game | Java | Individual Project | 2022
  - Used Factory and Strategy patterns for bots and dealers
  - Incorporated Artificial Intelligence concepts by changing dealer strategy in runtime.
- Data Structures and Algorithms | Java | Individual Project | 2022
  - o Created data structures such as Linked List, Stacks, and Queues without in-built libraries
  - Used these data structures to create Breath First and Depth First Search algorithms
- Container Yard Game | C | Individual Project | 2022
  - Created a series of computational functions that collaboratively created the operation of the game.
- Website Portofolio | HTML, CSS, JavaScript | Individual Project | 2022-2023
  - Created a website that effectively displays by love and passion for software engineering!

## TISHA NAICKER. (she/her)

### 3RD YEAR SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT









naicker.tisha@gmail.com

@tishanaicker

tnai255

https://tnai255.github.io/TishaNaickerPortfolio/

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Worley Professional Engineering Scholarship Recipient (2022)
- University of Auckland Top Achiever Scholarship (2021)
- Botany Downs Secondary College DUX (2020)

#### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Critical Thinking: My Engineering degree and the subjects I took in high school required a high level of critical thinking, such as analysing and problem-solving.
- Creativity: My favourite hobbies are art visual, digital, and dancing.
- Teamwork: My prior job was heavily team-focused, and my past leadership roles in school have all been team-oriented.
- Communication: Growing up in church and having leadership roles in school has equipped me to build connections with people from various demographics.
- IT skills: I completed four years of Digital Technology in school, where most of my grades were excellences.
- Organisation: My grades are a product of being highly organised with my study habits and techniques.
- · Proficient in MS Office.
- Full License Driver

#### **CO-CURRICULAR EXPERIENCE**

In high school, I was in a leadership role where I was responsible for running and organising assemblies as well as being in charge of the academic committee. I participated in Indian and African dance, played Netball, mentored a student through COVID, and was involved in the math, outreach, and environmental committees. In church, I am part of the technology and creative team where I am in charge of audio and visual some Sundays and I have helped with mentoring young people.

#### **INTERESTS**

In my spare time, I love to draw, paint, and do digital art! I really enjoy making handcrafted keepsakes, so these are my favourite outlets to do so. I love my Fijian Indian culture and embrace it by giving importance to staying connected to my cultural roots such as by speaking Hindi. Being a woman in engineering can be hard but I am enormously proud to be part of that minority, so I go to various Women in Engineering events to meet individuals like me! I am also heavily involved in my c3 church community and actively do volunteer work as a part of that.

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

I am bilingual, so I am fluent in Hindi and English! Hindi being my native language.

#### REFEREES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST